generative AI with large language models.
Large language models or LLMs
大型语言模型或LLMs是一项非常令人兴奋的技术。
are a very exciting technology.
But despite all the buzz and hype,
然而，尽管各种新闻和炒作满天飞，许多人仍
然低估了它们作为开发者工具的能力。
one of the thing that is still underestimated by
many people is their power as a developer too.
Specifically, there are
具体来说，过去我需要花费数月时间构建的许多机器学习
和AI应用，现在你可能只需要几天甚至几周就能完成。
many machine learning and AI
applications that used to take me
in days or maybe even small numbers of weeks.
This course will take a deep dive with you into how
这门课程将和你一起深入研究LLM技术的工作原理，
LLM technology actually works
including going through many of the technical details,
包括详解许多技术细节，如模型训练，指令调整，微调，
the generative AI project life cycle framework to
以及生成式AI项目生命周期框架，帮助你规划和执行你的项目等等。
help you plan and execute your projects and so on.
Generative AI and LLMs
生成式AI和LLMs是一种通用技术。
specifically are a general purpose technology.
That means that similar to
这意味着它们与其他通用技术（如深度学习和电力）类似，
other general purpose technologies
like deep learning and electricity,
is useful not just for a single application,
它不仅对单一应用有用，
but for a lot of
而且对许多不同的应用也有用，这些应用覆盖了经济的许多领域。
different applications that span
many corners of the economy.
started maybe 15 years ago or so,
there's a lot of important where it lies ahead of us that
我们面前还有许多重要的工作需要由许多人花费多年的时间来完成，
needs to be done over many years by many people,
to identify use cases and build specific applications.
Because a lot of with this technology is so
因为这项技术还非常新，很少有人真正知道如何使用它，
new and so few people really know how to use them,
many companies are also right
许多公司现在也在急着寻找和雇佣那些真
正懂得如何用LLMs构建应用的人才。
now scrambling to try to find and
hire people that actually know
how to build applications with LLMs.
I hope that this course will also help you,
我希望这门课程也能帮助你，
if you wish, better position
如果你愿意的话，可以更好地定位自己去获得一份相关的工作。
yourself to get one of those jobs.
I'm thrilled to bring you this course along with
我很高兴能够带来这门课程，一同教授的
还有来自AWS团队的一群出色的导师，
[inaudible] who are here with me today,
他们包括今天在我身边的Antje Barth、Mike Chambers、
Shelbee Eigenbrode，以及第四位导师Chris Fregly，
as well as a fourth instructor Chris Freby,
who will be presenting sort of adds.
他将会进行一些附加的讲解。
Antje and Mike above generative AI developer advocates.
Antje和Mike是生成式AI开发者倡导者。
Shelbee and Chris above
Shelbee和Chris是生成式AI解决方案架构师。
generative AI solutions architects.
All of them have a lot of
他们都有丰富的经验，
experience helping many different companies build many,
帮助过许多不同的公司使用LLMs构建了许多创新的应用。
I look forward to all of them sharing
我期待他们在这门课程中分享这些丰富的实践经验。
this rich hands-on experience in this course.
We've develop the content for
我们在开发这门课程的内容时，
this course with inputs from
many industry experts and applied scientists at Amazon,
参考了来自Amazon、AWS、HuggingFace以及世界各地
顶级大学的许多行业专家和应用科学家的意见。
AWS, Hugging Face and
many top universities around the world.
Antje, perhaps you can say a
Antje，也许你可以进一步介绍一下这门课程。
bit more about this course.
Sure. Thanks Andrew.
好的。谢谢Andrew。
It's a pleasure to work with you again on this course and
很高兴再次与你在这门课程上合作，
the exciting area of generative AI.
这是一个关于生成式AI的激动人心的领域。
With this course on
在这门有关大型语言模型生成人工智能的课程中，
generative AI with large language models,
we've created a series of
我们为AI爱好者，工程师或数据科学家设计了一系列课程。
lessons meant for AI enthusiasts,
engineers, or data scientists.
Looking to learn the technical foundations
如果你希望学习LLMs的技术基础，以及训练，调整和
部署它们的最佳实践，那么这门课程正适合你。
as well as the best practices behind training,
tuning, and deploying them.
In terms of prerequisites,
我们假设你已经熟悉Python编程，以及基本的数据科
学和机器学习概念，这是学习这门课的先决条件。
Python programming and at least
basic data science and machine learning concepts.
If you have some experience with
如果你已经有一些Python或TensorFlow的经验，那应该足够了。
either Python or TensorFlow, that should be enough.
In this course, you will explore in detail the steps that
在这门课程中，你将详细探讨构成典型
生成式AI项目生命周期的各个步骤，
make up a typical generative AI project lifecycle,
from scoping the problem and
从定义问题和选择语言模型，到优化模型部署和集成到你的应用中。
optimizing a model for
deployment and integrating into your applications.
This course covers all of the topics,
这门课程涵盖了所有的主题，
not just at a shallow level,
不仅是浅层次的，
but we'll take the time to make sure you come
我们不仅会浅尝辄止，而且会确保你深入理解所有这些技术，
away with a deep technical understanding of
all of these technologies and be well-positioned to
让你在构建自己的生成式AI项目时真正知道自己在做什么。
really know what you're doing when you
build your own generative AI projects.
Mike, why don't you tell us
Mike，你能告诉我们的学员每周将看到什么内容吗？
a little bit more details about
what the learners will see in each week?
Absolutely, Antje. Thank you.
当然，Antje，谢谢。
In Week 1, you will examine
在第一周，你将研究驱动大型语言模型的Transformer架构，
the transformer architecture that
powers large language models,
explore how these models are trained,
探索如何训练这些模型，并了解开发这些强大的LLMs所需的计算资源。
and understand the compute resources
required to develop these powerful LLMs.
You'll also learn about
你还会了解一种叫做上下文学习的技术，
a technique called in-context learning.
How to guide the model to output
如何通过Prompt工程在推理时引导模型输出，
the most important generation parameters
of LLMs for tuning your model output.
In Week 2,
在第二周，
you'll explore options for adapting pre-trained models to
你将探索如何通过一种称为指令微调的过程，
将预训练模型适应到特定的任务和数据集。
specific tasks and datasets via
Then in Week 3,
you'll see how to align
然后在第三周，
the output of language models with
你将看到如何将语言模型的输出与人类价值观对齐，
human values in order to increase
helpfulness and decrease potential harm and toxicity.
以增加其实用性并减少潜在的伤害和毒性。
Though we don't stop at the theory.
where you'll be able to try out these techniques for
每周都包括一个动手实验，
all the resources you need for working with
large models at no cost to you.
而且你可以免费实验这些技术。
Shelbee, can you tell us a little
Shelbee，你能告诉我们更多关于动手实验的信息吗？
bit more about the hands-on labs?
Sure thing, Mike. In the first hands-on lab,
当然可以，Mike。在第一个动手实验中，
you'll construct a compare
在第一个动手实验中，你将构建并比较
给定生成任务的不同Prompt和输入，
different prompts and inputs for a given generative task,
in this case, dialogue summarization.
在这个案例中，是对话摘要。
You'll also explore different inference parameters
你也会探索不同的推理参数和采样策略，以了
解如何进一步改善生成模型的返回结果。
and sampling strategies to gain
intuition on how to further
improve the generative model of responses.
you'll find tune it existing
你将微调一个现有的来自HuggingFace（一
个流行的开源模型库）的大型语言模型。
large language model from Hugging Face,
a popular open-source model hub.
You'll play with both full fine-tuning and
你将同时使用完全微调和参数有效微调（简称PEFT）。
parameter efficient fine tuning or path for short.
You'll see how puffed lets you
你将看到PEFT如何让你的工作流程更加高效。
make your workflow much more efficient.
In the third lab, you get hands-on with reinforcement
在第三个实验中，你将通过人类反馈进行强化学习（RLHF），
learning from human feedback or RLHF,
you'll build a reward model classifier to label
你将构建一个奖励模型分类器来标记
模型的返回结果是有害还是无害。
model responses as either toxic or non-toxic.
Don't worry if you don't understand
如果你现在还不理解所有这些术语和概念，也不用担心。
all these terms and concepts just yet.
You'll dive into each of these topics in
你将在这门课程中深入探讨每一个主题。
much more detail throughout this course.
I'm thrilled to have Antje, Mike,
我很高兴有Antje，Mike，Shelbee以及Chris
来向你们介绍这门深入探讨LLMs的课程。
Shelbee as well as Tris presenting this course to
you that takes a deep technical dive into LLMs.
You come away from this course having practice with
你将从这门课程中获得很多关于如何构建或
使用LLMs的具体代码示例的实践经验。
many different concrete code examples
for how to build or use LLMs.
I'm sure that many of the code snippets will
我相信其中许多代码片段将直接用于你自己的工作。
end up being directly useful in your own work.
I hope you enjoy the course and use what
我希望你能喜欢这门课程，并利用你学到
的知识构建一些真正令人兴奋的应用。
you learn to build some really exciting applications.
diving into how LLMs
are being used to build applications.